pphosted.com 2014-06-08

# Proofpoint Privacy Policy

## This Privacy Policy is effective as of February 13, 2014

Proofpoint understands the importance of safeguarding your privacy and we take this responsibility very seriously. We are providing the following Privacy Policy to inform you of our policies and procedures for the collection, use and disclosure of any information about you that we collect via www.proofpoint.com (this "Site") or by other means.

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the changes taking effect.

In this policy, "using" and "processing"information includes using cookies on a computer, subjecting the information to statistical or other analysis and using or handling information in any way, including without limitation collecting, storing, evaluating, modifying, deleting, using, combining, disclosing and transferring information within our organization or among our affiliates within the United States or internationally.

Proofpoint, Inc. has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please first contact the Proofpoint Privacy Policy Administrator at [privacy@proofpoint.com](mailto:privacy@proofpoint.com). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request)

Proofpoint, Inc. complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Proofpoint, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Proofpoint's certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

### Information We Collect and Use

Our primary goals in collecting information are to provide and improve our products and services, to provide quality customer service, to contact companies whose representative has indicated an interest in receiving information about Proofpoint products and to enable users to effectively navigate the Site.

We may collect your contact information in the following ways: if you sign up for a free 45 day trial, offers on the Site, newsletters, download white papers from the Site, respond to a promotion offered by a Proofpoint partner or send us an email. Such contact information includes first and last name, title, company name, industry type, mailing address, telephone number, fax number, email address and company size (" ** _Contact Information_** "). We may also collect information about your mailbox size, which will allow us to classify your company by size. We may combine your Contact Information with information collected from others in order to improve the quality and value of our products and services, and to analyze and understand how our Site is used.

We also use your Contact Information to contact you with certain marketing or promotional materials, as well as other information that may be of interest to you. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications.

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or by emailing us at [privacy@proofpoint.com](mailto:privacy@proofpoint.com).

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [privacy@proofpoint.com](mailto:privacy@proofpoint.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

| 

**Blog**  
If you use the blog on this Web site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these blogs, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these blogs. To request removal of your personal information from our blog, contact us at [privacy@proofpoint.com](mailto:privacy@proofpoint.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Customer Testimonials**  
We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial.

**Log Data**  
When you visit the Site, we automatically collect technical and statistical data about your visit, such as your browser type, the pages you visit and any search terms you use (" ** _Log Data_** "). We also collect your public IP address when you visit the Site. We may use your public IP address in order to determine whether certain requests are fraudulent or frivolous and we may automatically cross-reference your public IP address with your domain name (usually the domain name of your ISP or employer). Because you may be visiting the Site from your personal residence (for example, because you are telecommuting), your IP address and any associated domain name are treated as " ** _Personal Network Information_** "instead of Contact Information. "Log Data" does not include Personal Network Information. Although such Personal Network Information may be used to administer and maintain the Site, it is not shared with any third parties, except as described below in the sections titled "Service Providers," "Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement" and "Business Transfers." We will use Log Data for any purpose.

**Aggregated Information**  
In addition, we may cull certain data from within the set of Contact Information, Personal Network Information and Log Data we collect from you and combine that information with information we collect from other Proofpoint users and customers (collectively the " ** _Aggregated Information_** ") in order to improve the quality and value of Proofpoint product offerings and to analyze and understand how our Site is used.

**Cookies**  
Like many websites, we use "cookies" to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer's hard disk for record keeping purposes. We utilize session ID cookies to enable certain features of the Site, to better understand how you interact with the Site, and to monitor aggregate usage by Proofpoint users and web traffic routing on the Site. Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted from your computer when you close your browser. You can instruct your browser, by editing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Site or all functionality of the service. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

**Third Party Cookies**  
The use of cookies by third parties is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Third parties use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site.

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)**  
Our third party advertising partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information.  
  
---|---  
  
### Information Sharing and Disclosure 

From time to time we may share your Contact Information (name, email address, phone number) with our authorized channel partners so that they can provide you with information on goods or services that may be of interest to you. You can, at any time, update your information and/or opt out of receiving such communications by visiting <http://www.proofpoint.com/id/update-info/index.php>, filling in your information and modifying "Opt out of sharing info with third parties."  
We may share Aggregated Information (after stripping of any information that would personally identify you) and Log Data with third parties for industry analysis, demographic profiling, and other purposes. 

| 

**Service Providers and Partner Websites**  
We may from time to time use certain third party companies and individuals to perform Site-related services (for example, without limitation, website hosting, maintenance services, database management, Web analytics, and improvement of the Site's features) (service providers). These third party service providers have access to your Contact Information, Personal Network Information, and Log Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose. If you further are routed or otherwise make any web-browsing selection that takes you to another party's website you will be subject to the terms of such third party privacy policy for any activities that you conduct while on that third-party service.

**Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement**  
Proofpoint cooperates with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose your Contact Information, Personal Network Information, and Log Data to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including without limitation subpoenas and notice of class certification), to protect the property and rights of Proofpoint or a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop any illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity.

**Business Transfers**  
If Proofpoint is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.  
  
---|---  
  
### Changing or Deleting Your Information

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update or delete it by emailing our Customer Support at [privacy@proofpoint.com](mailto:privacy@proofpoint.com). We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

### Security & International Transfer 

Proofpoint is very concerned with safeguarding your information. We employ administrative, physical, procedural, and technological measures designed to protect your information from unauthorized access. Your information may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country, or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, Proofpoint transfers your Contact and Personal Network Information to the United States and processes it there. Your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

### Links to Other Sites

Our Site contains links to other websites. If you click on a third-party link you will be directed to that third party's website. We do not exercise control over third-party websites. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. This Privacy Policy addresses the use and disclosure of information that we collect from you through this Site. Other sites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personal information you submit to them. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit. The fact that we link to a website is not an endorsement, authorization, or representation of our affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices.

### Social Media Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

### Our Policy Toward Children

This Site is not directed to children under 18. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with personal or contact information without their consent, he or she should contact us at [privacy@proofpoint.com](mailto:privacy@proofpoint.com). If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we will delete such information from our files immediately. 

### Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

Proofpoint, Inc.  
Attn: Customer Service  
892 Ross Drive   
Sunnyvale, CA 94089
